Finding Aid for Learning Disabilities Association of Michigan, Washtenaw County Chapter records, 1968-1998
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Learning Disabilities Association of Michigan, Washtenaw County Chapter records 1968-1998
Learning Disabilities Association of Michigan. Washtenaw County Chapter.
2.5 linear feet
8540 Bh 2
Articles of incorporation, membership lists, minutes, reports, newsletters, correspondence, newspaper clippings, photographs, and other organizational materials.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated by the organization (donor no. 6408 ) beginning in 1980. Additions have been received.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The organizational has undergone at least two name changes: from the Association for Children with Social and Learning Difficulties, then the Michigan Association for Children and Adults with Learning Difficulties, later the Learning Disabilities Association of Michigan.
Organizational records include minutes, correspondence, and administrative materials relating to the activities of the Washtenaw County chapter.
Subjects:
Learning Disabilities Association of Michigan. Washtenaw County Chapter.; Child development--Michigan.; Education--Michigan.; Learning disabilities.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Learning Disabilities Association of Michigan. Washtenaw County Chapter.; Children and adults.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Organizational Records
  - Constitution, articles of incorporation (plus amendment), and other legal documents (Box 1)
  - Legal materials (Box 1)
  - Purpose of organization
    - Members (Box 1)
    - Membership lists Mailing lists (Box 1)
    - Directories (Box 1)
    - General meeting attendance sheets (Box 1)
  - Annual reports, 1971-1972, 1972-1973, 1982-1998 (Box 1)
  - Minutes
    - Advisory Board meetings, 1969, 1970, 1971, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Executive Board meetings, 1968-1989, 12 folders (Box 1)
    - General meetings (Box 1)
  - Treasurer reports, 1969 and miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Newsletters, 1968-1981, 7 folders (Box 1)
    (recent newsletter separately cataloged)
  - Brochures, miscellaneous publications (Box 1)
  - Forms and questionnaires (Box 1)
  - Proposals
    - Service Center (Box 1)
    - Professional directorship (Box 1)
    - Funding (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Projects
    - Pilot project (Box 1)
    - Project Outreach (Box 1)
    - Survival Coffees for parents (Box 1)
  - Studies
    - Ann Arbor Advisory Committee on Special Needs (Box 1)
    - WISD "Need Study Committee" report (Box 1)
    - Pre-school study (Box 1)
    - Washtenaw County Community Coordinated Child Care (Box 1)
  - Grant, United Fund ACSLD-WARC (Box 1)
  - Recreation program (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1979, 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous printed material (Box 1)
  - News clippings, 1972-1975, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Unsorted material (Box 2)
  - Photographs (Box 2)
  - Later unprocessed records (Box 3)